<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The server that runs on Bitcoin!</title>
    <description>Bitquest is a Survival style Minecraft server with a Bitcoin-denominated economy: Players can buy, sell and trade items using BTC micropayments with a fully funcional Bitcoin wallet you can send money to/from. To start playing, Connect to the following address using the PC Version of Minecraft: play.bitquest.co
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 20:45:12 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 20:45:12 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The wither challenge is awaiting for the craziest warriors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/wither.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today servers have been updated with a special event: The hunt for withers, who have invaded the bitquest and dogequest spawn cities. The server will reward with 100 bits to anyone who can save the city from this vicious monsters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help the Wither hunters, their location will be revealed in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://discord.gg/jvJ624c&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt;, so be sure to be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules of the event are simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A wither will appear only when the loot facuet is &amp;gt; 400 Bits/DOGE. A discord bot will send the location once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The player who can fight and deliver the final blow to the wither will be awarded 100 Bits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100% of BTC paid to villager shops and land purchases go to the loot faucet!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the location of the monsters, our discord bot will announce the challenge winners and other stats about the game.
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/discord-bot.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like this event and you’d like more, please consider donating to the BitQuest project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, thanks for playing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/14/the-wither-challenge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/01/14/the-wither-challenge.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New beta update: PETS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Bitquest community!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce a new beta update: PETS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 100 bits you can adopt a fluffy furry bestial friend: an ocelot.  It might follow you around chunks and spawns with you every time you die lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to own a kitty, use the command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
/pet &amp;lt;nameofyourpet&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works in both servers: &lt;strong&gt;play.bitquest.co&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;doge.bitquest.co&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this is a beta feature and is not finished yet, so expect your new friend to be a little glitchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you adopt more than one kitty, the last one will be yours. The others will be released to freedom!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to improve this feature in the next versions with ideas from the community. Please share your ideas through our channels ;D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for playing!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/selfie-pet.png&quot; alt=&quot;Selfie pets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/12/new-update-pets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/06/12/new-update-pets.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BitQuest supports Dogecoin. Such currency, very server!</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-content&quot; itemprop=&quot;articleBody&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://gallery.mailchimp.com/5f8be72ce6c44eb5f1b21584e/images/987388fa-4cf0-4460-9017-0d0ccbf7b163.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;doge built in Bitquest, Minecraft server&quot; title=&quot;Bitquest and Dogecoin&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi fellow BitQuesters!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dogecoin is a notable cryptocurrency. It’s a clone of an old version the Bitcoin network, with one difference: it inflates at a rapid pace with no limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Bitcoin entered the mainstream and became less accesible, players have asking us to open alternative servers in other cryptocurrencies, so we decided to experiment with Dogecoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note this server is considered “alpha testing” and we recommend you don’t use it to store large amount of coins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a small refaction of the BitQuest code, it’s finally compatible with Dogecoin and you can connect to our brand new doge server in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;doge.bitquest.co&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Using Minecraft: Java Edition 1.12)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like always, is possible to use our open source code to create your own dogecoin server! &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitquest/bitquest&quot;&gt;you can learn more in our GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About the Bitcoin server… Worry not! There’s no plan to discontinue or replace the world of BitQuest, and both will be receiving the same updates.&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;style&gt;
          body {
            font-family:'Comic Sans MS' !important;

          }
          h1,h2,h3,h4 {
            font-family:'Comic Sans MS' !important;
    

          }
      &lt;/style&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 19:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/05/bitquest-dogecoin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/05/bitquest-dogecoin.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BitQuest 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-full-img&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/tqZEwpL.png&quot; alt=&quot;Satoshi Town, also known as &amp;quot;the spawn&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new BitQuest, version 2.0 is finished. The goal of this release was to make the integration of Bitcoin into Minecraft simple, open, and hackable. I am sure this is far from perfect, but a really fun new way to play Minecraft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go ahead and tell you what’s new and different!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-chain-wallets&quot;&gt;On-Chain wallets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-side-img side-l&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/UM6nLpU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Wallet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before 2.0, we were accounting player’s balance ‘off chain’: A database of debits, credits, and balances. The good side of this, is we can handle a huge amount of transactions, because we didn’t need to upload every one of them to the Blockchain, which induces fees and confirmation time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with that solution is that we have to keep track of every transaction, secure and segregate wallets, and produce checks for potencial duplications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now use “on chain” transactions, which means everything is uploaded to the Blockchain and all the information about the server economy is out there in the open for everyone to account for where the money is, and where it goes (more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having an on chain wallet also means you can do player-to-player transactions without the server being the middleman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad side is transactions are a little slow, there’s a limit on how many we can do and sometimes you have to wait confirmation times to spend bits. There are a number of Bitcoin enhancements coming in the future that will make things better, and we are looking into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To handle all transactions, we use the excellent tools of our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blockcypher.com&quot;&gt;BlockCypher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-markets-and-loot&quot;&gt;New Markets and Loot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-side-img side-r&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/jmUsfeg.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Buying diamond and Elytra&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Satoshi Town you can buy valuable stuff with Bitcoin, like food or the latest Elytra wings. Each comes at a different price, though. But the interesting part is what happens to the Bitcoin spent in items!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Market transactions go to a “World” wallet. Each time a monster is killed, a small number of calculations (and luck) might substract 200 bits from that wallet directly to yours, a small reward for your braveness. If you choose to spend that money again inside the Market, it will go back to the world wallet, rewarding another player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the transactions are now on-chain, you can look into the world wallet and explore the raw operations of the game economy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://blockchain.info/address/1BiWdDaHChaKTcNXWs3nxPRcxb6CHM5h2u
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;land-ownership&quot;&gt;Land Ownership&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;post-side-img side-l&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/4dfEhu2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Extending the empire&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past BitQuest, land was free but ubiquitous. So many players claimed plots and never got back, leaving construction projects unfinished and deadly traps; Also, the community was growing and server space shrinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this new version, a land “chunk” of 16x16 blocks can be bought at the price of 200 bits (or 0.0002BTC); This transaction goes straight to the administrator as a contribution for server maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can claim contiguous chunks to make big areas, even cities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitquest-is-also-a-plugin&quot;&gt;BitQuest is also a plugin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you can play BitQuest in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitquest.co&quot;&gt;the official server&lt;/a&gt;, the project was re-written from scratch as a plug-in just because a single, but very important goal: To allow anyone to make their own Minecraft Bitcoin servers. It matches the latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://spigotmc.com&quot;&gt;Spigot&lt;/a&gt; API and compatible with Mac/PC/Linux vanilla Minecraft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, it’s a little rough and undocumented but very soon we’ll have JAR and Docker Image in line with last stable BitQuest for deployment with minimum configuration. We hope this attracts collaborators as well expand the Bitcoin gaming universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that inside the next generation of virtual worlds, money will be an inter-operable, open, transparent asset backed by the Blockchain, like Bitcoin. A game money we can spend outside a specific world, perhaps in other games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assets bought inside video games, like weapons or land ownership should be stored on the blockchain, and players must have freedom to sell or barter those assets inside or outside the system without restrictions or fees, just like any real world stuff you buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much work to do and BitQuest is just a tiny fraction. This release would be impossible without the help of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shallonhackenb1&quot;&gt;Airiellis&lt;/a&gt;, Burntone, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Xeyler&quot;&gt;Xeyler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juanj&quot;&gt;juanj&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RagingMouser&quot;&gt;RagingMouser&lt;/a&gt; and everyone on the BitQuest slack team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BitQuest plugin is open source that you can fork or contribute on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitquest/bitquest&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt;, And if you want to support BitQuest even further, your donations are appreciated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;qr-code-container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://chart.googleapis.com/chart?chs=300x300&amp;amp;cht=qr&amp;amp;chl=bitcoin:3A1hmUUqCUV7SdftvVpWc8jQ3xmGqBPGeZ&quot; alt=&quot;3A1hmUUqCUV7SdftvVpWc8jQ3xmGqBPGeZ&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;span&gt;3A1hmUUqCUV7SdftvVpWc8jQ3xmGqBPGeZ&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 16:17:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/19/bitquest-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/05/19/bitquest-2.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BitQuest is now Open Source</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;BitQuest started as an experiment to create a Bitcoin economy inside Minecraft and we have not only demonstrated how Bitcoin and Blockchain technology can be best game money in the world, but started the best community of players and collaborators we could ever hope for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce that BitQuest 2.0 Beta testing has started, This is a complete rewrite of the project that works as a Spigot plugin, and completely Open Source under the Apache-2.0 License.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check the official repository here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitquest/bitquest&quot;&gt;https://github.com/bitquest/bitquest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means the game mechanics and economy are completely transparent, we’ll be open to collaborations via pull requests to improve the game, everyone is welcome to fork and make their own Minecraft servers fuelled with the power of Bitcoin as an in-game economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to thank the folks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://xapo.com&quot;&gt;Xapo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blockcypher.com&quot;&gt;BlockCypher&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Xeyler&quot;&gt;Xeyler&lt;/a&gt;, the BitQuest Slack and &lt;a href=&quot;http://mego.cl&quot;&gt;Mego&lt;/a&gt; for helping on this huge re-launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to see you on the brand new BitQuest.
Merry Christmas!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 17:17:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/21/welcome-to-the-bitquest-2.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/12/21/welcome-to-the-bitquest-2.0.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BitQuest 2.0 is coming soon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi fellow BitQuesters!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been quiet for a period of a few months, and we are deeply sorry for all of you guys who felt abandoned, but the time has come to re structure this project and find the best way to achieve the great ideas we have for this server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 2 months we’ve been writing the server code from scratch, which was a arduous task to implement a new design. We all know that BitQuest 1.0 had a lot of bugs and problems with Bitcoin and most of the problems originate due to the very fact that the Minecraft engine is not designed to handle any type of in-game currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the past year we have come up with a strategy to make the server a lot more stable and easier to mantain, however, this new design requires completely different technology and the need to rewrite most of the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also learnt that there is a lot of people who want to support the project via donations, code contributions and lending free servers and we think the best vehicle to allow contibutions, transparency and resillience to the project is to make it open source. That way the contributions will help not only make BitQuest the best Minecraft server in the world, also allowing other people to make their own BitQuests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on, all the game code resides on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/bitquest/bitquest&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, so we can all keep track of the development process and (more importantly) get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe Bitcoin is gonna be the official currency of virtual worlds, hands down. And while still in its infancy, this is the time to experiment integrating this new technology and keeping BitQuest closed is not a cool way to contribute to the Bitcoin community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, My main task will be to help new developers get started by documenting the code and tools, creating spaces for discussion of the future of the project and keeping a transparent, organized, democratic organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, my company (&lt;a href=&quot;http://mego.cl&quot;&gt;MEGO&lt;/a&gt;) will be sponsoring this project with production, testing and development servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited for the future of this project, but it will come faster and greater with a bigger team. If you want to join the moderators or dev team, please drop me a line at cristian@mego.cl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for playing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 17:17:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/07/starting-bitquest-2.0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/12/07/starting-bitquest-2.0.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
